<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/4.5.1" created="2016-04-29 15:54" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/"
>

<channel>
	<title>My Blog 2016 – work comp</title>
	<link>http://localhost:8888/blog</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 15:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://localhost:8888/blog</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://localhost:8888/blog</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></wp:author_login><wp:author_email><![CDATA[seb_cgl_bailey@hotmail.co.uk]]></wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>

	<wp:category><wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id><wp:category_nicename><![CDATA[uncategorised]]></wp:category_nicename><wp:category_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:category_parent><wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></wp:cat_name></wp:category>
	<wp:term><wp:term_id><![CDATA[1]]></wp:term_id><wp:term_taxonomy><![CDATA[category]]></wp:term_taxonomy><wp:term_slug><![CDATA[uncategorised]]></wp:term_slug><wp:term_parent><![CDATA[]]></wp:term_parent><wp:term_name><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></wp:term_name></wp:term>

	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.5.1</generator>

	<item>
		<title>Sample Page</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/sample-page__trashed/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 08:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?page_id=2</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[This is an example page. It's different from a blog post because it will stay in one place and will show up in your site navigation (in most themes). Most people start with an About page that introduces them to potential site visitors. It might say something like this:

<blockquote>Hi there! I'm a bike messenger by day, aspiring actor by night, and this is my blog. I live in Los Angeles, have a great dog named Jack, and I like pi&#241;a coladas. (And gettin' caught in the rain.)</blockquote>

...or something like this:

<blockquote>The XYZ Doohickey Company was founded in 1971, and has been providing quality doohickeys to the public ever since. Located in Gotham City, XYZ employs over 2,000 people and does all kinds of awesome things for the Gotham community.</blockquote>

As a new WordPress user, you should go to <a href="http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-admin/">your dashboard</a> to delete this page and create new pages for your content. Have fun!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>2</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-22 09:45:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-22 08:45:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[sample-page__trashed]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[trash]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[page]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_page_template]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[default]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_trash_meta_status]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_trash_meta_time]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1461661929]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_desired_post_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[sample-page]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Welcome To My Blog!</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/04/01/welcome-to-my-blog/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=5</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Writing a blog is one of those things that everyone thinks they need to do, or at least should be doing. But why? Some people do it to pass the time, some for business, and some people, well I just have no idea why they bother - I mean there are some seriously weird and wacky mumblings out there on the interweb. I suppose everyone has their niche market though, and as long as one person reads it, it’s a success in my eyes. Not everybody is going to be interested in my blog for example, but I want to do it anyway, and hopefully it will be of some interest to other designers and developers out there.

<!--more-->
<h2>SO WHAT ARE THE REASONS PEOPLE WRITE BLOGS</h2>
<h3>1. To make money.</h3>
A lot of blogs have an e-commerce aspect to them where individuals can sell, well, whatever they want! You could be a chef (or at least a passionate amateur cook) looking to sell your own cookbooks or even to sell yourself as a caterer. How about a fashion designer looking to sell some of your clothing designs, or offering your services to design bespoke wedding dresses or suits? A photographer wanting to sell some prints to the masses? Even big companies use their blogs to make money, using their name for a platform for anyone willing to pay them for the exposure. No matter what size company/brand you have, a blog is a great way to earn a bit of extra dollar - all you need is a following.
<h3>2. As a journalist.</h3>
Journalism isn’t just about working for The Times or the newest cool magazine, it is about shouting about information you think people deserve or want to know about. This could be breaking news stories from across the globe, or just talking about your next-door-neighbours cat getting stuck in the tree in your front garden again. However big or small the story is, the likelyhood is, somebody is going to read it and that can give bloggers a huge sense of satisfaction.
<h3>3. To stay in touch.</h3>
The world is a well travelled place nowadays, and what with the popularity of “Gap Yaahs” for younger people, it’s no wonder that there are a huge amount of ‘Travel Blogs.’ But how do they stay in touch with those people back home? How do they let everyone know exactly what they have been up to on their trips to far off rainforests and biking across Vietnam? With a blog. I’d be surprised to learn if there was a single person in London that didn’t know somebody else from a different country. It’s great to know that we live in such a diverse city, but surely they all miss their families and friends from home? Well, a blog is a great way to keep in contact with them and share their experiences, even if they are the complete other side of the world. Sometimes it is hard to give them a ring and writing something online, that can be accessed 24/7 by anyone, is the simplest way to tell them about everything. (It also saves you from repeating the story for the 50th time to the 4-times-removed aunt that you last saw when you were 2 years old).
<h3>4. A place for thoughts.</h3>
These are normally the most interesting reads of them all. The ones that aren’t really for any particular reason, but just for a bit of fun. To jot down your everyday thoughts to share with the world. These tend to interest me more because the people writing them don’t care so much about how they come across, or how many follows they get on twitter, but genuinely just want to share their views with their friends and people around the world. The subjects covered in these tend to vary a lot more too - making you want to stay on the site and read more and more (even if you are sitting at your desk at work pretending to do the research for that next project).
One of my favourites of all time is lookatmyfuckingredtrousers.blogspot.co.uk – It’s just the brilliant findings of photos of people in red trousers. That’s it. No more, no less. Hilarity ensues.
<h3>5. As a platform for your professional career.</h3>
As much as it may not sound like it so far, this is the one I’m hoping for this blog to become. With a lot of careers these days, especially for designers, you need to have a huge amount of knowledge about what is going on in the big bad world. It can be a seriously daunting task to try and find out what’s been happening recently when you go to an interview for a new job, or even just to prove you know your stuff with your colleagues. So what better way to get up-to-date on the latest trends and what other people are talking about than to write a blog yourself? You may have ideas for articles to write for the next year, but eventually you will run out of those ideas and need to find something new to write about to keep your posts coming and followers returning (which in turn will boost your SEO and help potential employers and clients find you easier). Making yourself write something new on a regular basis will mean you need to go out there and find something to talk about. Brilliant! Two birds with one stone - you know your stuff, and you can boost your SEO (Search Engine Optimisation, for those of you not web-savvy) at the same time!
<h2>SO! WHAT IS THERE TO COME?</h2>
I see this blog as a mixture of no.s 4 and 5 above. I want to be able to post things that don’t necessarily fit in with my portfolio, some case studies for projects that I’m particularly proud of, or even working on at the moment. I’m also always coming across cool little coding hacks or just simple things that I haven’t thought of before, and I want to be able to share those with like-minded people and create short tutorials. They might even be thoughts about life in general, or things I’ve recently seen out and about that I want to mention. Hopefully, after a few months of doing this blog I might even try and get some guest bloggers writing something, but who knows, this might be a complete flop!

So expect to see:
<ul>
 	<li>Codebits/ Tutorials</li>
 	<li>Thoughts and ramblings</li>
 	<li>Infographics</li>
 	<li>New tech/ design trends</li>
 	<li>Case Studies</li>
</ul>
&nbsp;

If you ever have any comments or queries about anything that I write about please feel free to email me.

So, welcome to my blog! I hope you enjoy reading the thoughts of a mad man!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Blog post number 1! My official first post for the blog on sebastianbailey.co.uk. Find out some reasons for writing a blog, and why I am doing this one.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>5</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-04-01 12:00:22]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-04-01 11:00:22]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[welcome-to-my-blog]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Why I Taught Myself To Code</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/04/02/why-i-taught-myself-to-code/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 11:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=7</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Coming from a more artistic background, I never quite imagined myself coding, or getting too technical with computers. Although I have (and always have had) a much higher sway towards computer design, rather than the finer arts, I was quite happy just using the various software. Apart from a short phase in my teenage years, my art and architectural experience has been based in the Adobe Creative Suite and a couple of different CAD softwares.

<!--more-->
<h2>SO WHY DID I MAKE THE DECISION TO DIVE INTO THE SCARY WORLD OF CODE AND WEB DEVELOPMENT?</h2>
Two reasons really:
<h3><b><u>1.</u></b></h3>
I’ve always been good with computers, and tried out the basics of HTML and CSS when I was younger and really enjoyed it, so it just seemed like a logical thing to do.
<h3><b><u>And 2.</u></b></h3>
It really is the future of design in my opinion. Every day, more and more people are using smartphones and tablets to do… more and more. While they have become such a huge part of our lives in the recent years, it occurred to me that the best way to really get my work out there and to have an impact on peoples lives is to learn to code so I could take advantage of this.

It’s always been an interest of mine to be able to affect the way people live and interact with themselves, their surroundings and other people through the medium of design. Everything people use in life has had some sort of design input to it, whether it be the computer or phone you are using to read this, the chair you are sitting on, the clothes you are wearing, or even the building you are in. With the different design potentials of these objects, comes different ways people use them, affecting their everyday life. This fascinates me.

At this point you might be thinking, “But what does that have to do with coding? You’re just talking about design!”

When it comes to my designs and work, I like to be in control of everything. I like to paint the whole picture, not just edit the masterpiece, if that makes any sense. I wouldn’t be content with just doing the designs for a web project for example (even though I have in the past, and trust me when I say, I was itching around like a child hopped up on sherbert sticks) - I have an idea in my head with how everything works and looks and interacts with the user, and I would much prefer to be able to do that myself, rather than telling somebody else. So when I design something that I want people to interact with, I want to be in complete control of the project.
<h2>SO WHAT MADE ME FINALLY TAKE THE PLUNGE INTO THE ICE BATH THAT IS CODING?</h2>
I was bored in the job I was in at the time. I was doing meaningless task after meaningless task. Then I was asked to have a look at the designs for email campaigns that we were sending out. At first, I was only expected to just redesign the banners, but I thought, hang on a minute I remember doing some of this HTML and CSS stuff when I was younger, and it all came rushing back to me.
<blockquote>In my teenage years, I did as every other teenager did and set up a myspace account. Remember those times of going onto the profile editors? Picking out those garish neon colour schemes? Trawling google images for the best background? It was fun for about a day, but for me that wasn’t enough. It just looked awful. So I looked into more interesting myspace layouts and found the world that was the ‘div overlay.’ Oh I had so much fun creating layouts from scratch, trying to be a bit different (and in some cases being very samey samey - the standard photoshops of my favourite bands etc). But it opened me up into the world of HTML and CSS, and I would spend hours every night going through other people’s code figuring out what I could change and how I would make my own layouts. Eventually I uploaded some to the site www.createblog.com and got some great feedback (unfortunately in the many years since I’ve done these, myspace has changed hands and updated and it doesn’t allow for your own code anymore - getting rid of the one good thing left about it!).</blockquote>
So there I was, sat at my desk with an epiphany. Web and app design was the way forward for me. And so I began the journey back into HTML and CSS and very quickly discovered how hugely different the world of web design today was to the experience I had with those div overlay myspace layouts. For a few weeks I was just playing around with the code for these emails I had been asked to redesign, but I soon realised that I needed to branch out, and it soon came to whether I should just carry on teaching myself, or go on a course.

Anyone else that has looked into learning to code will have come across this problem too. Is going on a course to learn it really necessary and worth the money? Well, it totally depends on the sort of person you are, but for me I was quite happy teaching myself (and to be honest really couldn’t afford to go on a course) so I looked for some online courses and came across codecademy.com - a truly brilliant site. It really helps take away that daunting aspect of getting into coding, and takes you through very small steps at a very basic level of various languages. It’s easy to follow, and is also a very well designed website in my opinion. Here is where I covered some more HTML and CSS - and finally got into HTML5 and CSS3 - a huge leap forward for me in terms of design.

The catch with codecademy though, is that it really is for beginners. I found myself finishing the HTML, CSS, Javascript and jQuery courses very quickly and still feeling a bit daunted by it all. But, I thought that I had just about enough knowledge to start a project, so I built a prototype app for my work. Diving head first, straight into the code, from scratch, really brought my skills on leaps and bounds from those basic courses, and I was ready to do my first public website - my personal portfolio. I’d gathered enough knowledge to get the basics done, and build a simple website for myself, and managed to get it done in just a few days. Don’t get me wrong, it’s far from perfect, but the speed at which you learn when you just jump straight into a project with the basic knowledge of a few languages is incredible, and extremely rewarding when it’s ready to go live.

&nbsp;

Yes, it was daunting at first, and yes it was a bit of a shock to the system. But in the end, it’s definitely been worth it.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Getting a little bit more serious after the first post. Find out why I taught myself to code and how I got into it.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>7</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-04-02 12:00:02]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-04-02 11:00:02]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[why-i-taught-myself-to-code]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Tutorial - Box-Shadow CSS3 Animated Button</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=9</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=9</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<style type='text/css'>

.css-button div {
	font-size: 20px;
	padding: 10px 20px;
	background: white;
	-webkit-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s
	-moz-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	-o-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
}

.css-button {
	margin: 15px auto;
	width: 200px;
	text-align: center;
}

.button-one div {
	position: relative;
	top: 0;
	left: 0;
	color: #255fd2;
	border: 4px solid #255fd2;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2, -1px 1px 0 #255fd2, -2px 2px 0 #255fd2, -3px 3px 0 #255fd2, -4px 4px 0 #255fd2, -5px 5px 0 #255fd2, -6px 6px 0 #255fd2, -7px 7px 0 #255fd2, -8px 8px 0 #255fd2;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2, -1px 1px 0 #255fd2, -2px 2px 0 #255fd2, -3px 3px 0 #255fd2, -4px 4px 0 #255fd2, -5px 5px 0 #255fd2, -6px 6px 0 #255fd2, -7px 7px 0 #255fd2, -8px 8px 0 #255fd2;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2, -1px 1px 0 #255fd2, -2px 2px 0 #255fd2, -3px 3px 0 #255fd2, -4px 4px 0 #255fd2, -5px 5px 0 #255fd2, -6px 6px 0 #255fd2, -7px 7px 0 #255fd2, -8px 8px 0 #255fd2;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2, -1px 1px 0 #255fd2, -2px 2px 0 #255fd2, -3px 3px 0 #255fd2, -4px 4px 0 #255fd2, -5px 5px 0 #255fd2, -6px 6px 0 #255fd2, -7px 7px 0 #255fd2, -8px 8px 0 #255fd2;
}
.button-one div:hover {
	top: 8px;
	left: -8px;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #255fd2;
}

.button-two div {
	position: relative;
	top: 0;
	left: -16px;
	color: #d9462b;
	border: 4px solid #d9462b;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b, 1px 1px 0 #d9462b, 2px 2px 0 #d9462b, 3px 3px 0 #d9462b, 4px 4px 0 #d9462b, 5px 5px 0 #d9462b, 6px 6px 0 #d9462b, 7px 7px 0 #d9462b, 8px 8px 0 #d9462b;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b, 1px 1px 0 #d9462b, 2px 2px 0 #d9462b, 3px 3px 0 #d9462b, 4px 4px 0 #d9462b, 5px 5px 0 #d9462b, 6px 6px 0 #d9462b, 7px 7px 0 #d9462b, 8px 8px 0 #d9462b;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b, 1px 1px 0 #d9462b, 2px 2px 0 #d9462b, 3px 3px 0 #d9462b, 4px 4px 0 #d9462b, 5px 5px 0 #d9462b, 6px 6px 0 #d9462b, 7px 7px 0 #d9462b, 8px 8px 0 #d9462b;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b, 1px 1px 0 #d9462b, 2px 2px 0 #d9462b, 3px 3px 0 #d9462b, 4px 4px 0 #d9462b, 5px 5px 0 #d9462b, 6px 6px 0 #d9462b, 7px 7px 0 #d9462b, 8px 8px 0 #d9462b;
}
.button-two div:hover {
	top: 8px;
	left: -8px;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #d9462b;
}

.button-three div {
	position: relative;
	top: 16px;
	left: -16px;
	color: #6c9f02;
	border: 4px solid #6c9f02;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02, 1px -1px 0 #6c9f02, 2px -2px 0 #6c9f02, 3px -3px 0 #6c9f02, 4px -4px 0 #6c9f02, 5px -5px 0 #6c9f02, 6px -6px 0 #6c9f02, 7px -7px 0 #6c9f02, 8px -8px 0 #6c9f02;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02, 1px -1px 0 #6c9f02, 2px -2px 0 #6c9f02, 3px -3px 0 #6c9f02, 4px -4px 0 #6c9f02, 5px -5px 0 #6c9f02, 6px -6px 0 #6c9f02, 7px -7px 0 #6c9f02, 8px -8px 0 #6c9f02;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02, 1px -1px 0 #6c9f02, 2px -2px 0 #6c9f02, 3px -3px 0 #6c9f02, 4px -4px 0 #6c9f02, 5px -5px 0 #6c9f02, 6px -6px 0 #6c9f02, 7px -7px 0 #6c9f02, 8px -8px 0 #6c9f02;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02, 1px -1px 0 #6c9f02, 2px -2px 0 #6c9f02, 3px -3px 0 #6c9f02, 4px -4px 0 #6c9f02, 5px -5px 0 #6c9f02, 6px -6px 0 #6c9f02, 7px -7px 0 #6c9f02, 8px -8px 0 #6c9f02;
}
.button-three div:hover {
	top: 8px;
	left: -8px;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #6c9f02;
}

.button-four div {
	position: relative;
	top: 16px;
	left: 0;
	color: #855c00;
	border: 4px solid #855c00;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00, -1px -1px 0 #855c00, -2px -2px 0 #855c00, -3px -3px 0 #855c00, -4px -4px 0 #855c00, -5px -5px 0 #855c00, -6px -6px 0 #855c00, -7px -7px 0 #855c00, -8px -8px 0 #855c00;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00, -1px -1px 0 #855c00, -2px -2px 0 #855c00, -3px -3px 0 #855c00, -4px -4px 0 #855c00, -5px -5px 0 #855c00, -6px -6px 0 #855c00, -7px -7px 0 #855c00, -8px -8px 0 #855c00;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00, -1px -1px 0 #855c00, -2px -2px 0 #855c00, -3px -3px 0 #855c00, -4px -4px 0 #855c00, -5px -5px 0 #855c00, -6px -6px 0 #855c00, -7px -7px 0 #855c00, -8px -8px 0 #855c00;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00, -1px -1px 0 #855c00, -2px -2px 0 #855c00, -3px -3px 0 #855c00, -4px -4px 0 #855c00, -5px -5px 0 #855c00, -6px -6px 0 #855c00, -7px -7px 0 #855c00, -8px -8px 0 #855c00;
}
.button-four div:hover {
	top: 8px;
	left: -8px;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 #855c00;
}

.example-one {
	border: 4px solid red;
	font-size: 20px;
	padding: 10px 20px;
	background: white;
	color: red;
}

.example-two {
	margin-bottom: 12px;
	border: 4px solid red;
	font-size: 20px;
	padding: 10px 20px;
	background: white;
	color: red;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
}

.example-three {
	margin-bottom: 12px;
	border: 4px solid red;
	font-size: 20px;
	padding: 10px 20px;
	background: white;
	color: red;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-webkit-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	-moz-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	-o-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;
}

.example-three:hover {
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
}

.example-four {
	margin-bottom: 12px;
	position: relative;
	top: 0;
	left: 0;
	border: 4px solid red;
	font-size: 20px;
	padding: 10px 20px;
	background: white;
	color: red;
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
	-webkit-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s
	-moz-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	-o-transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
	transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
}

.example-four:hover {
	-webkit-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	-moz-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	-o-box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
	top: 8px;
	left: -8px;
}

</style>


Earlier this year, I came across an an awesome little CSS trick through Mailchimp’s annual summary for their customers.

<!--more-->

They had these awesome retro style buttons:

&nbsp;
<div class="css-button button-one"><div>Click Me!</div></div>
&nbsp;

Naturally, I thought:
<blockquote>“Ooooohh! I want to learn how to do that and include it in some of my projects.”</blockquote>
So I checked out the code for it in developer tools and found out it was a lot simpler than I initially thought.

They were taking advantage of the CSS3 property ‘box-shadow’ and repeating it at incremental pixels to create the 3d box effect. This box shadow was then transitioned to nothing on hover to create the button.
<h3>SO LET’S GET STARTED…</h3>
<p id="step-one"><u><em>Step 1.</em></u></p>
Create the button element with whatever text you want.
<div class="well"><code>&lt;button class=“my-button”&gt;Click Me&lt;/button&gt;</code></div>
<div class="example"><div>Click Me</div></div>
&nbsp;
<p id="step-two"><u><em>Step 2.</em></u></p>
Style the button however you want - borders, colors, fonts etc. (Chrome users might want to add in the extra bit of css at the bottom to get rid of the blue click state of <code>&lt;button&gt;</code>s)
<div class="well"><code><code>.my-button {
color: red;
background: white;
font-size: 20px;
padding: 10px 20px;
border: 4px solid red;
}</code></code>.button:focus {
outline: 0;
}</div>
<div class="example"><div class="example-one">Click Me</div></div>
&nbsp;
<p id="step-three"><u><em>Step 3.</em></u></p>
Add in the box-shadow, incrementally seperated by 1px at a time, each time seperated by a comma. (Make sure all the vendor-prefixes are there too if you want to support the slightly older browsers!) The first value is the 'left' offset value, the second is the 'top' offset value, and the third is the blur value (this should always be 0).
<div class="well"><code>.my-button {
color: red;
background: white;
font-size: 20px;
padding: 10px 20px;
border: 4px solid red;
box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
}</code></div>
I think adding in about twice as many pixels in the box-shadow as the width of the button's border is a good ratio. So as the border is 4px in width, the box-shadow should go up to '-8px 8px'.
<div class="example"><div class="example-two">Click Me</div></div>
&nbsp;
<p id="step-four"><u><em>Step 4.</em></u></p>
Here is where you add the transition to the hover effect. (Again, don't forget your vendor prefixes!)
<div class="well"><code><code>.my-button {
color: red;
background: white;
font-size: 20px;
padding: 10px 20px;
border: 4px solid red;
box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s;
}</code></code>.my-button:hover {
box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
}</div>
<div class="example"><div class="example-three">Click Me</div></div>
&nbsp;
<p id="step-five"><u><em>Step 5.</em></u></p>
The last thing left to do now is to add in the positioning of the element so it looks like a proper button being clicked (instead of the backwards effect it has at the moment). Make sure the <code>top</code> and <code>left</code> properties have the same timings as the box shadow, otherwise it won't quite look right.
<div class="well"><code><code>.my-button {
position: relative;
top: 0;
left: 0;
color: red;
background: white;
font-size: 20px;
padding: 10px 20px;
border: 4px solid red;
box-shadow: 0 0 0 red, -1px 1px 0 red, -2px 2px 0 red, -3px 3px 0 red, -4px 4px 0 red, -5px 5px 0 red, -6px 6px 0 red, -7px 7px 0 red, -8px 8px 0 red;
transition: box-shadow 0.2s ease 0.001s, top 0.2s ease 0.001s, left 0.2s ease 0.001s;
}</code></code>.my-button:hover {
box-shadow: 0 0 0 red;
top: 8px;
left: -8px;
}</div>
<div class="example"><div class="example-four">Click Me</div></div>
&nbsp;

So there you have it! One retro flat style CSS3 button. Enjoy!

<script type='text/javascript'>
$(document).ready(function(){
	var buttonClicked = 0;
	$('.css-button').click(function(){
		if (buttonClicked == 0) {
			$('.css-button').addClass('button-two').removeClass('button-one');
			buttonClicked = 1;
		}
		else if (buttonClicked == 1) {
			$('.css-button').addClass('button-three').removeClass('button-two');
			buttonClicked = 2;
		}
		else if (buttonClicked == 2) {
			$('.css-button').addClass('button-four').removeClass('button-three');
			buttonClicked = 3;
		}
		else if (buttonClicked == 3) {
			$('.css-button').addClass('button-one').removeClass('button-four');
			buttonClicked = 0;
		}
	});
});
</script>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[A tutorial for a cool little retro style animated button using CSS3 box-shadow property.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>9</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-04-14 12:00:46]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-04-14 11:00:46]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[tutorial-box-shadow-css3-animated-button]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[66]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Why I Won&#039;t Be Using Uber Again</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/04/30/why-i-wont-be-using-uber-again/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2015 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=11</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Yesterday, I had the very unfortunate experience of getting my Uber account hacked, and somebody was charging their taxi journeys to my card.

<!--more-->

Over the last few days, Twitter has been exploding with people saying their Uber accounts have been hacked, and they are getting receipts for journeys that they haven't made - some people's bills racking up into the hundreds, and even thousands!

<a title="Uber accounts for sale on the dark web" href="http://motherboard.vice.com/read/uber-accounts-for-sale-on-the-dark-web">Word on the street</a> is that there has been a security breach and the detail's of thousands of London Uber users' details (emails and passwords) are now being sold on the dark web - single account details being sold for ~$5 and bulk purchases also available.

So my experience of this is that I woke up to a text in the middle of the night saying:
<blockquote>"Your Uber account information has been updated (email, password). If you didn't make this change, email support@uber.com."</blockquote>
I was a bit shocked by this but I was shattered and it was like 1am so I decided it was a mistake and went back to sleep. When I woke up for work in the morning I had a notifaction from Uber which oddly was a receipt for a taxi that I had supposedly taken at 2am costing me £9.

Now I'm one of the lucky ones - I've seen pictures of receipts in the hundreds for journeys that have lasted a couple of hours - obviously the idiot that had my details wasn't a seasoned criminal (they even used UberX and not one of the classier cars!).

Needless to say, I emailed support asking for my password to be reset so that this person could be locked out. Here's where I got angry...

I didn't get a reply for a couple of hours and when I eventually did, I was told that they couldn't discuss details of an account with someone who doesn't own it... Sorry, what?! I do own the account... OH WAIT! The email was changed to a throwaway one so my email is no longer associated with my account.

Luckily for me, I had signed up for Uber with Facebook, so I could still log in and change my associated email back to the correct one and email them back. But what would have happened if I had signed up via email? I would have no idea what email or password was now being used to get into my account, never being able to log back in.

While waiting for another reply from the support team (cue, another few hours) I got another text... the exact same one as before. He was at it again! this time, we were both awake and going back and forth changing the email in my account from my real one, to his/her throwaway one. They had also ordered another cab, which I got a notifaction for - I could see pickup location and destination in the app, which funnily enough was not too far from work - oh how I was tempted to go and meet them at the drop-off! But no, I cancelled 3 cabs before they managed to get in one.

<div class="img-full">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/uber-screenshot.png" alt="Uber screenshot of hacked journeys" />
<div class="img-caption">These two trips that someone took on my account - glad it was only £15 and I noticed on the day it was being done!</div>
</div>

Obviously, I wasn't going to let the bastard get away with it so I rang up my bank and cancelled my card straight away. But here's where the problem lies...

&nbsp;
<h3>1. What would have happened if they changed my mobile number and I didn't get a text saying that my details had been changed?</h3>
<h3>2. With a different email, phone number, password... everything - I wouldn't have found out that someone was using my account until my next bank statement.</h3>
<h3>3. They could have got away with a hell of a lot more than £15 of taxi journeys (I was too late on the 2nd one)</h3>
&nbsp;

Again, I'm lucky. Some people have had it a hell of a lot worse - hundreds/thousands being charged to their accounts. I'm just fortunate the person who bought my details was a dumbass.

&nbsp;
<h2>EVEN THOUGH I MANAGED TO GET IT UNDER CONTROL, AND THEY DID EMAIL BACK, I HAVE LOST MY TRUST IN THEM</h2>
I've realised how sensitive the data is that Uber take from people - and for a start-up to handle such information really isn't the best thing to do, and I realise that now. They obviously don't have the resources to have proper security on their databases - which should be bank-encryption level as they are handling bank account details!

Not only was their customer support a pretty bad experience (cue, arsey email back asking to cancel my account once they eventually got back to me too late with a new password and refunds - I'd already had to cancel my card thank you!), what with <a title="Uber rape in Boston" href="http://time.com/3640027/uber-rape-boston/">reports of drivers being accused of rape</a> and<a title="Uber driver accused of assault was in prison" href="http://pando.com/2014/01/06/exclusive-uber-driver-accused-of-assault-passed-zero-tolerance-background-check-despite-criminal-history/">even doing time in prison</a>, it's become apparent to me that Uber is just getting too out of hand, and they can't handle the sheer amount of people using their service, and criminals slip through the gaps.

So really, I want to say thank you to the idiot who bought my account details, you actually saved me from something that could have gone a lot worse.

Join the debate on twitter with <a title="Twitter - #ubered" href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ubered?src=hash">#ubered</a> and <a title="Twitter - #boycottuber" href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23boycottuber">#boycottuber</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Uber are a terrible service that let their users' accounts get hacked and sold - racking up prices for journeys people didn't take into the thousands! Here's my experience and why I won't be using them again]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>11</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-04-30 12:00:22]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-04-30 11:00:22]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[why-i-wont-be-using-uber-again]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[65]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Tutorial - Simple CSS Parallax Effect</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=23</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2015 11:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=23</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So there are a few parallax libraries out there that do a wonderful job of adding the "trendy" effect to your website, and most of them pretty small in size too. But there is a very simple, little known, CSS property that can cause pretty much the same effect on a background image that most parallaxers (yes, I just made up a word for that... don't judge me!) use these libraries for.

<!--more-->

It's called: <code>background-attachment</code>

So simple this is, that adding just <b>one</b> line of code to your CSS can create a wonderful looking (albeit, basic) parallax effect on any page:
<div class="well"><code>background-attachment: fixed;</code></div>
<div class="example iframe-example"><iframe id="iframe" src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/css-parallax-example.html" width="300" height="150" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
The main thing to note with this however, is that you have to set the<code>background-size</code> to <code>cover</code>, and the "cover" effect is on the overall container. So you will notice that with the header, if the content is above the fold, then you will not see some of the header image. My suggestion to this would be to then make the 'header' div a 100% height, which is the common and stylish norm nowadays anyway.
<h2>So here is the code you need for the above example:</h2>
<h3>HTML:</h3>
<div class="well">
<pre><code>&lt;div class='example-header'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='content'&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;This is some content!&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='mid-strip'&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class='content'&gt;
	&lt;h2&gt;This is some more content...&lt;/h2&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</code></pre>
</div>
<h3>CSS:</h3>
<div class="well">
<pre><code>.header {
	height: 300px;
	width: 100%;
	background: url('**IMAGE URL**');
	background-size: cover;
	background-attachment: fixed;
	background-position: center;
}
.content {
	padding: 10px;
}
.mid-strip {
	height: 200px;
	width: 100%;
	background: url('**IMAGE URL**');
	background-size: cover;
	background-attachment: fixed;
	background-position: center;
}</code></pre>
</div>
Et voila! Enjoy your simple CSS parallax effect! :)]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Learn this super simple trick to get an easy parallax scrolling effect on your website with just one line of CSS code!]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>23</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-09-17 12:00:23]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-09-17 11:00:23]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[tutorial-simple-css-parallax-effect]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[draft]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Xd-cover</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2016/04/24/adobe-xd-review/cover/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 15:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/cover.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>53</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-26 16:49:08]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-26 15:49:08]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[cover]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>35</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/cover.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2016/04/cover.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:17:"2016/04/cover.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:17:"cover-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:17:"cover-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:17:"cover-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:18:"cover-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:19:"cover-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>hp-cover</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2016/03/15/always-judge-a-book-by-its-cover/hp/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 15:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/hp.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>54</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-26 16:53:29]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-26 15:53:29]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hp]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>32</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/hp.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2016/03/hp.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:640;s:6:"height";i:640;s:4:"file";s:14:"2016/03/hp.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:2:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:14:"hp-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:14:"hp-300x300.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:300;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>hover-cover</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/11/18/funky-hover-effects-desktop-only/hover-cover/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 15:55:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/hover-cover.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>55</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-26 16:55:07]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-26 15:55:07]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hover-cover]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>30</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/hover-cover.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/11/hover-cover.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1209;s:6:"height";i:644;s:4:"file";s:23:"2015/11/hover-cover.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:4:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"hover-cover-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"hover-cover-300x160.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:160;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"hover-cover-768x409.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:409;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"hover-cover-1024x545.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:545;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Suzuki Nine Knights 2014 presented by GoPro – Day 2 Heli Session</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/11/13/snowboarding-a-great-platform-for-designers/suzuki-nine-knights-2014-presented-by-gopro-day-2-heli-session/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 14:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/snowboarding-designers.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Seppe Smits]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>56</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:56:49]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 14:56:49]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[suzuki-nine-knights-2014-presented-by-gopro-day-2-heli-session]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>27</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/snowboarding-designers.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/11/snowboarding-designers.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1000;s:6:"height";i:666;s:4:"file";s:34:"2015/11/snowboarding-designers.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:3:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"snowboarding-designers-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"snowboarding-designers-300x200.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:200;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"snowboarding-designers-768x511.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:511;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:3:"5.6";s:6:"credit";s:12:"Klaus Polzer";s:6:"camera";s:8:"NIKON D4";s:7:"caption";s:11:"Seppe Smits";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:10:"1396369966";s:9:"copyright";s:15:"© Klaus Polzer";s:12:"focal_length";s:2:"86";s:3:"iso";s:3:"200";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:6:"0.0008";s:5:"title";s:66:"Suzuki Nine Knights 2014 presented by GoPro – Day 2 Heli Session";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:4:{i:0;s:6:"Action";i:1;s:11:"Seppe Smits";i:2;s:9:"Snowboard";i:3;s:24:"Suzuki Nine Knights 2014";}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>architecture-now</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/10/26/how-architecture-helped-me-get-to-where-i-am-now/architecture-now/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/architecture-now.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>57</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:04:01]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:04:01]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[architecture-now]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>25</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/architecture-now.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/10/architecture-now.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:28:"2015/10/architecture-now.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:28:"architecture-now-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:28:"architecture-now-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:28:"architecture-now-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:29:"architecture-now-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"architecture-now-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>architecture-now</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/10/26/how-architecture-helped-me-get-to-where-i-am-now/architecture-now-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/architecture-now-1.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>58</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:19:12]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:19:12]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[architecture-now-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>25</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/architecture-now-1.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/10/architecture-now-1.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:30:"2015/10/architecture-now-1.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"architecture-now-1-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"architecture-now-1-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"architecture-now-1-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"architecture-now-1-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:32:"architecture-now-1-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>do-dont-hear</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/08/24/what-a-graphic-designer-doesnt-want-to-hear-vs-the-perfect-client/do-dont-hear/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:23:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/do-dont-hear.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>59</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:23:35]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:23:35]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[do-dont-hear]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>21</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/do-dont-hear.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/08/do-dont-hear.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:24:"2015/08/do-dont-hear.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"do-dont-hear-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"do-dont-hear-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"do-dont-hear-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:25:"do-dont-hear-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:26:"do-dont-hear-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>designing-website</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/06/23/building-my-own-website-part-2-of-2/designing-website/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/designing-website.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>60</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:26:35]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:26:35]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[designing-website]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>19</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/designing-website.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/06/designing-website.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:29:"2015/06/designing-website.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:29:"designing-website-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:29:"designing-website-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:29:"designing-website-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:30:"designing-website-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"designing-website-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>architecture-stopped</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/27/architecture-why-i-stopped/architecture-stopped/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/architecture-stopped.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>61</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:27:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:27:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[architecture-stopped]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>17</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/architecture-stopped.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/05/architecture-stopped.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:32:"2015/05/architecture-stopped.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:32:"architecture-stopped-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:32:"architecture-stopped-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:32:"architecture-stopped-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"architecture-stopped-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"architecture-stopped-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>powpow</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/14/why-snowboarding-is-better-than-skiing-and-why-it-doesnt-matter/powpow/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:28:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/powpow.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>62</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:28:38]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:28:38]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[powpow]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>15</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/powpow.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/05/powpow.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:800;s:6:"height";i:555;s:4:"file";s:18:"2015/05/powpow.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:3:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:18:"powpow-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:18:"powpow-300x208.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:208;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:18:"powpow-768x533.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:533;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>designing-website-0</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/01/building-my-own-website-part-1-of-2/designing-website-0/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/designing-website-0.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>63</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:29:50]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:29:50]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[designing-website-0]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>13</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/designing-website-0.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/05/designing-website-0.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:31:"2015/05/designing-website-0.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"designing-website-0-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"designing-website-0-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:31:"designing-website-0-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:32:"designing-website-0-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"designing-website-0-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>designing-website-0</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/01/building-my-own-website-part-1-of-2/designing-website-0-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/designing-website-0-1.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>64</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:30:47]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:30:47]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[designing-website-0-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>13</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/designing-website-0-1.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/05/designing-website-0-1.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:33:"2015/05/designing-website-0-1.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"designing-website-0-1-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"designing-website-0-1-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:33:"designing-website-0-1-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:34:"designing-website-0-1-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:35:"designing-website-0-1-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>uber</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/04/30/why-i-wont-be-using-uber-again/uber/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/uber.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>65</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:31:47]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:31:47]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[uber]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>11</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/uber.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/04/uber.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:16:"2015/04/uber.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:16:"uber-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:16:"uber-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:16:"uber-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:17:"uber-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:18:"uber-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>css-button</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/?attachment_id=66</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 15:35:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/css-button.jpg</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>66</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-27 16:35:02]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-27 15:35:02]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[closed]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[css-button]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[inherit]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>9</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[attachment]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<wp:attachment_url><![CDATA[http://localhost:8888/blog/wp-content/uploads/2015/04/css-button.jpg]]></wp:attachment_url>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attached_file]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2015/04/css-button.jpg]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_attachment_metadata]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:5:{s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:4:"file";s:22:"2015/04/css-button.jpg";s:5:"sizes";a:5:{s:9:"thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:22:"css-button-150x150.jpg";s:5:"width";i:150;s:6:"height";i:150;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:6:"medium";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:22:"css-button-300x169.jpg";s:5:"width";i:300;s:6:"height";i:169;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:12:"medium_large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:22:"css-button-768x432.jpg";s:5:"width";i:768;s:6:"height";i:432;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:5:"large";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:23:"css-button-1024x576.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1024;s:6:"height";i:576;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}s:14:"post-thumbnail";a:4:{s:4:"file";s:24:"css-button-1920x1080.jpg";s:5:"width";i:1920;s:6:"height";i:1080;s:9:"mime-type";s:10:"image/jpeg";}}s:10:"image_meta";a:12:{s:8:"aperture";s:1:"0";s:6:"credit";s:0:"";s:6:"camera";s:0:"";s:7:"caption";s:0:"";s:17:"created_timestamp";s:1:"0";s:9:"copyright";s:0:"";s:12:"focal_length";s:1:"0";s:3:"iso";s:1:"0";s:13:"shutter_speed";s:1:"0";s:5:"title";s:0:"";s:11:"orientation";s:1:"0";s:8:"keywords";a:0:{}}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2016/04/22/hello-world__trashed/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 08:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=1</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-22 09:45:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-22 08:45:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[hello-world__trashed]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[trash]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_trash_meta_status]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_trash_meta_time]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1461661072]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_desired_post_slug]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[hello-world]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_wp_trash_meta_comments_status]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:1:{i:1;s:1:"1";}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>1</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Mr WordPress]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>https://wordpress.org/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date><![CDATA[2016-04-22 09:45:18]]></wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-22 08:45:18]]></wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Hi, this is a comment.
To delete a comment, just log in and view the post&#039;s comments. There you will have the option to edit or delete them.]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved><![CDATA[post-trashed]]></wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type><![CDATA[]]></wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Building My Own website (Part 1 of 2)</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/01/building-my-own-website-part-1-of-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 11:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=13</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[My personal website was my first full website project that I would be building from scratch and doing everything myself, and for that reason was a little daunting for me to start.

<!--more-->

I had been teaching myself to code for over a month by this point, and I already had some HTML and CSS knowledge from email campaigns in my job, but to build the project up from scratch was a whole new experience for me. So I would like to share with everyone how I went about building my website, the problems I encountered and what I did to solve them.

I suppose the first thing I should cover is why I decided I needed a website and why I felt it necessary to build it myself rather than just use a standard wordpress theme as a platform for a portfolio.
<h2>WHY DID I DECIDE IT WAS TIME FOR ME TO HAVE A WEBSITE?</h2>
<h3>1. I wanted to have a bit of fun and show off my new skills</h3>
It's all good and well stating on my CV that I know some HTML and CSS because I've done a few myspace layouts years ago, but what does that really show? That I did exactly the same as everyone else did when they were that age? I could have been amazing at coding when I was younger, but the fact that it was when I was younger would mean that I didn't carry it on and I might not know the first thing about web development now! HTML and CSS has come on light years since I was 15, and pretty much everything that I did and knew back then has become irrelevant in today's world of web design.

I had been catching up on my HTML and CSS knowledge after playing around with some email campaigns at work, and after learning a bit more about them and getting up to date with the current trends, I realised that there was a lot more to web design and development than just knowing the basics of HTML and CSS. I taught myself Javascript and jQuery, knowing that a small amount of interactivity goes a long way with engaging an audience. I read up on responsive design and got to grips with the fundamentals of media queries - unfortunately this didn't help much with the email campaigns as media queries are rendered useless with a lot of email clients. So with all these new skills of mine, I thought what better way to show them off than to build my own personal website from scratch, including all of these within the project.
<h3>2. I could use it as an extension of my CV</h3>
Nobody likes to get large attachments as CVs. As a designer, this problem is a very common one. How to create a great looking CV and portfolio and send it off to potential employers while keeping everything at a relatively small file size. I would say a general rule of thumb would be that the CV should definitely be under 1MB, and everything together under 5MB. Anything more than that will start clogging up their inboxes and they might just delete it straight away for being annoying or just using up too much space.
<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://static1.businessinsider.com/image/4e01142f49e2ae6c69100000-1200/same-for-this-one.jpg" alt="Graphic Design CV that is over the top" />
<div class="img-caption">Some CVs are just over the top and I can imagine that if this is a good quality PDF, it would be over 1MB</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://www.designinfographics.com/infographics-images/graphic-design-resume.png" alt="Graphic Design CV that is good, but too much!" />
<div class="img-caption">This CV is has loads of information and looks like it could be quite a big file size as a PDF - nobody will accept a PNG or JPEG as a CV!</div>
</div>
</div>
Creating a website to act as my CV and portfolio alleviates this problem. These days (and especially in my profession), the majority of people have easy and fast access to the internet (whether that be on their phone or desktop), and so having this online just makes sense. Don't get me wrong, I'm not suggesting people should solely rely on an online CV and portfolio - it is always a good idea to have hard copies and PDF formats of these too (not only is this a preference of some people but having both can only enhance your chances of impressing an employer - show that you can design in more than one way!).
<h3>3. I needed something in my portfolio to do with web design</h3>
Even at the time of writing this, I am still very new to web development and design. I still have minimal projects under my belt and wanting to go into it as a career, I needed to have something to show for my expertise. Building it from scratch not only helped me to learn more about what I was doing, but it serves as an example as to what I can do.
<h2>WHY BUILD IT FROM SCRATCH RATHER THAN USE WORDPRESS OR ANOTHER WEBSITE BUILDER?</h2>
<h3>1. Wordpress is too common and doesn't necessarily show a full set of skills</h3>
Not a lot of HTML and CSS knowledge is necessarily needed to build your own website. All you need to do is follow a quick video tutorial on how to install Wordpress and bam! you have yourself a shiny new website all slick and working nicely. Building it from scratch has taught me more about coding, it has meant that I stumbled upon problems and I have had to figure out how to fix them myself - again teaching me more and helping me get into more of a coding mindset.
<h3>2. When I first started, I didn't know any PHP</h3>
If I was to use Wordpress, I would have liked to build my own theme and just use it as a CMS system, rather than helping me launch my website. But when I started building my website, I had very minimal PHP knowledge and thought it best to get it out there quicker, being able to build it myself, rather than teaching myself a whole new language and delaying the release of my website. I may need to switch to Wordpress or another CMS system in the future if this blog is any success, as it is just a lot easier to manage, but for now, I have no problem with doing everything from scratch and using the PHP I now know to host my website and blog.

&nbsp;
<h2>THE PROCESS OF BUILDING SEBASTIANBAILEY.CO.UK</h2>
<h3>1. What to include</h3>
My first decision was what my website should actually include. Did I want it to just be a CV? If I was to include my portfolio within it, what work should I include and how much? Making these decisions helped me later on in the design process and kept me stuck on a path.
<h3>2. Wireframe sketches</h3>
At first, my sketches for the wireframing of the site were to have it as a page by page website. There was a splash page, a menu page, a cv page, a seperate portfolio menu page, then individual pages for each of the portfolio sections. There were a lot more pages than there are in the final version. I did start going down this route with the designs, but half way through I realised that although the pages looked nice, and were very simple, it was pointless to have a seperate page for a lot of the aspects of the website. I knew that a fair amount of people would be viewing my website on mobile devices (45% at this point), and realised that having so many click throughs could be irritating. As each of these pages were very simple and all except for the individual portfolio pages had minimal images within them, it would make sense to merge them all into one page and have the majority of my website as a single page.
<div class="img-full">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-sketches.jpg" alt="Sketches for my initial designs for my website" />
<div class="img-caption">Here are a few of the sketches that I did as initial thoughts for the design of my website.</div>
</div>
<h3>3. Mock-up designs</h3>
As mentioned above, I did start mocking up the designs as per the wireframe sketches, but realised that half way through I wanted to make it a single page website, with only the portfolio pages seperated from the rest. The only design that this really affected was the menu, but including them all in one page meant that it was natural to make the menu more like the rest of the layout.
<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-home.png" alt="Wireframe design - Home" />
<div class="img-caption">Initial design for the home page of my website.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-contact.png" alt="Wireframe design - Contact" />
<div class="img-caption">Initial design for the contact page of my website.</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="img-full">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-menu.png" alt="Wireframe design - Menu" />
<div class="img-caption">Initial design for the menu page. This is the only design that drastically changed after switching to a one-page layout.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-cv.png" alt="Wireframe design - CV" />
<div class="img-caption">Initial design for the CV page.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-wireframe-portfolio.png" alt="Wireframe design - Portfolio" />
<div class="img-caption">Initial design for the portfolio pages (one each for Architecture, Graphic Design, Web Design and Photography).</div>
</div>
</div>
This is where I really got to nail the aesthetic of my brand and I spent quite a long time drawing different icons and choosing the correct colours to use. Using SVGs in my website also made me really perfect my logo and these icons - getting rid of any kinks and poorly drawn elements. This really cleaned up and simplified the artwork and imagery, helping reinforce my brand and design aesthetic.
<h3>4. Starting to code up the HTML and CSS</h3>
Given the style of layout of my website, I decided to use Bootstrap, as I saw it pointless building something else when Bootstrap was already perfect for my layout. However, me being me and liking to do a lot of the work myself, I only used Bootstrap for the purposes of the collumn layout - everything else was done using my own CSS.
<div class="img-full">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-code-css.png" alt="Coding up my website - HTML and CSS" />
<div class="img-caption">Starting to code up my website - the HTML and CSS.</div>
</div>
<h3>5. Adding in the scripts for interactivity</h3>
The majority of the HTML and CSS ran without a hitch - it was when I started to add in the various scripts I use throughout the site that the problems started to arise. The main one being with the layout for the portfolio pages (I will be doing a tutorial on combining LazyLoad and Masonry in the near future).
<div class="img-full">

<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/website-code-js.png" alt="Coding up my website - JS" />
<div class="img-caption">Adding in the scripts for the interactivity. This was where it started getting trickier!</div>
</div>
&nbsp;

I feel like the problems I came across and how I fixed them deserve their own post, so...

<a href="http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/06/23/building-my-own-website-part-2-of-2/">"to be continued..."</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Why I decided to create a website for myself and the problems I came across doing it. Part 1 explains my decisions for building a website and the initial design and coding.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>13</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-05-01 12:00:55]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-05-01 11:00:55]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[building-my-own-website-part-1-of-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[64]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Why Snowboarding is better than Skiing (and why it doesn&#039;t matter!)</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/14/why-snowboarding-is-better-than-skiing-and-why-it-doesnt-matter/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 11:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=15</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[For years, there's been a debate between snowboarders and skiiers as to which sport is better. I'm a keen snowboarder so I will obviously sway towards that side - BUT! I do think skiing is seriously fun too. I want people to appreciate both sports, but in my honest opinion I think it is skiiers that need to understand why snowboarding is so great, and that we aren't all a bunch of "wanks on planks", so let's go into some of the reaons why it is just so damn good:

<!--more-->
<h2>1. THE POWPOW</h2>
POWDER! Oh glorious, soft, rideable clouds. There's a reason why so many of us boarders talk about this so much. There is no other feeling in the world like gliding down a beautifully ungroomed fresh dump of snow. It's like angels have had a pillow fight in heaven and the feathers thrown up in the air have fallen down and landed gracefully and perfectly onto the softest (and largest) mattress on earth. Quite possibly the closest a human will ever get to flying or zero friction. Just tell me that doesn't sound like bliss?

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<a title="Pinterest - Backcountry snowboarding" href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/368873025699407559/"><img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/backcountry-snowboard-powder.jpg" alt="Snowboarder in powder" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">Floating on what feels like nothing - there really is nothing quite like it</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<a title="Volcom - Instagram" href="https://instagram.com/volcomsnow/"><img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/volcom-insta-park.jpg" alt="Snowboarders in a Park" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">Even though I'm not particularly good in a park I won't lie - it is sick!</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2>2. THE PARKS</h2>
Ask a kid where he/she wants to go on a nice sunny day... the park right? That's because it's the most fun a kid will get! (well, when I was a kid anyway, it's probably more like "NO! I wanna stay inside and play on my iPad!" nowadays. Eugh.) So there's a reason why they call it a PARK. Because it's the closest an adult can get to that full on childhood state of nirvana when running around the local park and climbing all over the frames and slides, and... damn, I want to be a kid again! Anyway, without snowboarding, snow parks wouldn't exist. Infact, before snowboarding there wasn't even any such thing as freestyle - it was all downhill. (apart from aerial skiing, which I think we can all agree is the least 'cool' snowsport ever. yes, including curling).
<h2>3. THE LOOK</h2>
Anyone I've ever asked has always said, even if they truly hate snowboarding and boarders, that it looks way sicker. It's just a fact. Although I'm certainly not saying everyone looks good snowboarding...

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<a title="The Art of Flight - Snowboard Movie" href="http://www.artofflightmovie.com/"><img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/snowboard-jump-aof.jpg" alt="Snowboard Jump" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">I mean come on...</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<a title="Shit Skiers Say" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=apNKEhdokKM"><img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/ski-boots-fail.gif" alt="Ski boots on stairs" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">FAIL. Need I say more?</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2>4. THE BOOTS</h2>
Easy, we can actually walk down the road at a normal pace and not make weird orgasm noises every time we take our boots off.
<h2>5. THE COMMUNITY</h2>
Boarders (nearly) always respect each other. We all have a mutual understanding beyond the grasp of any slightly close-minded skier who refuses to acknowledge this beautiful sport as a sport. I have to admit though you do get the occasional idiot. But don't worry skiers, we don't like them either! They bring us a bad name, so please don't assume we all hate everyone not on one board on the slopes.
<h2>6. THE PULL</h2>
Let's be honest here, if it wasn't for snowboarding coming onto the scene, skiing would have stayed as a sport reserved for the rich or those who live in the mountains. Bringing the appeal to the white hills has brought in more youth and therefore a bigger following of all winter sports, not just snowboarding! It's helped broaden skiing into more areas, and bring it to the masses.
<h2>7. HELPING SKIING</h2>
Following on from my last point, it has helped to expand skiing as a sport. It's brought freestyle to it, which in my opinion is why so many young people still start doing it - they want to be able to fly through the air and look as sick as some of the athletes they see on youtube. The form of a snowboard has also helped build new skiis. It's widened powder skiis - realising that the wider the ski the better and more fun in powder! (They basically wear two snowboards on their feet now). And the twin tips of freestyle skiis - allowing skiiers to (finally!) ski backwards!

&nbsp;

So there you have it... the many great reasons why snowboarding is so awesome! And a few arguments back at the skiiers who think things like, "yeah but skiing looks sick now too because we have freestyle and stuff!" And? Snowboarders invented it, and still push the sport every single day further and harder.

But who cares?! I've done both and will continue to for the rest of my life. They are both amazingly fun, and I will want to teach my children both so they can understand the differences (both good and bad) and hopefully make them better skiers and boarders overall.

As long as people are enjoying the slopes together that's all that matters. Why should it matter if I'm a "wank on a plank" or a "dick on 2 sticks"? I'm enjoying myself and hope everyone else is too. Peace. :)

&nbsp;

Keep on ridin' (and skiing).

And I'm just gonna leave these 2 videos here... pretty accurate actually.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/oPFet3a_Hno" width="100%" height="220" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>
<div class="img-caption">"Hold up! I Gotta strap myself in!"</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/apNKEhdokKM" width="100%" height="220" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe>
<div class="img-caption">"F*%£$ng Snowboarders!"</div>
</div>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Snowboarding is better than Skiing. Here's why! BUT skiing is pretty rad too.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>15</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-05-14 12:00:05]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-05-14 11:00:05]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[why-snowboarding-is-better-than-skiing-and-why-it-doesnt-matter]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[62]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Architecture – Why I Stopped</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/05/27/architecture-why-i-stopped/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=17</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[For a very long time I knew I wanted to be an Architect, so it surprised a lot of people when I packed it all in to become a graphic designer. For as long as I can remember it had been my dream job (apart from when I was a lot younger and I wanted to be things like an F1 driver, a Fireman and, rather oddly, a banker), so in some ways, it even surprised me that I wanted to give it up.

<!--more-->

My path to becoming an Architect started at a fairly young age, when I did some work experience for <a href="http://www.fosterandpartners.com/" target="_blank">Foster + Partners</a> before I had even taken my GCSE's, and one year later returning there and branching out to <a href="http://www.broadwaymalyan.com/" target="_blank">Broadway Malyan</a> too.

To become an Architect, you kind of need to start at such a young age because the A Levels needed to study it are fairly specific, and to be honest, not a very normal combination. Maths and Art are a must, and Physics is highly recommended. If you don't have these, then you can wave goodbye to your ideas of becoming an Architect, so deciding on taking them needs to be done early.

Even after doing some work experience, I was convinced it was what I wanted to do. I loved how much variety there could be in the work and all the considerations to take in when designing a building. I thought it was fascinating how you could shape how people move, interact and feel in their surroundings. It was still very much my career of choice.

So, naturally I was extremely excited to go to Cambridge to study Architecture - at the time being one of the top schools to study it. Then came actually doing the course, and I can't quite pinpoint the exact time I realised that it really wasn't for me at all, but I think it was about half way through the degree that it finally dawned on me.

Don't get me wrong, there were some really fun times, and it was a seriously up and down rollercoaster. But the bad times massively outweighed the good, and it just wasn't what I had hoped for. Everyone was lovely, the studio masters made it interesting, even the projects were intriguing and different - but I just didn't get the excitement that I should have done.
<h2>SO WHAT WAS IT THAT DIDN'T EXCITE ME?</h2>
<h3>1. All the process... none of the concept.</h3>
I think that a lot of the process I was used to from what I had been told about Architecture in the past and what I had gained from my work experience was all about the grand gesture and the concept of a project, and none of the itty gritty stuff that comes along with making something so intricate. Obviously, I understand that with the fun stuff, there always come something that nobody wants to do. But solving those problems interferred with my grand conceptual ideas and everyone seemed more interested in solving those problems than talking about what I wanted for the projects.
<h3>2. A distorted view of the profession</h3>
I also believe that I had been given a very warped view of what the career entailed for the average Architect. I did my work experience at the biggest and most succesful Architecture firm in the world, so it was only natural that they would have the most exciting projects and out of those would only want to show the best to their work experience interns. What I didn't realise at the time is that the average Architect will most likely work on dull council projects or small budget buildings that have a lot of criteria to fill - thus limiting their big ideas and grand gestures they would like to make with their buildings.
<h3>3. The stress</h3>
As dashing as I think I'll look with grey hair, I'd prefer to keep it at bay until atleast my mid 30's. And that definitely wouldn't happen with the amount of stress that comes with Architecture. I couldn't really handle the pressures of a degree, so I'd dread to think how I would deal with the Masters, let alone doing it for the rest of my life!
<h3>4. I found myself enjoying the more artistic side</h3>
Although I have always been quite mathematically enclined as a person, I suppose I've never quite been put in a position where so much of my time is needed to tick boxes, cross t's and dot i's. There is a lot of this with Architecture, both studying and I presume working, and I'm not somebody that likes jumping through hoops a lot. I like to push boundries and show my artistic side a bit more. I like to be in control and be quite 'out of the box' to use a cliché, and I felt like Architecture didn't quite give that to me.

&nbsp;

So there you have it. Although I did enjoy it at times (and there were quite a few of them), it just wasn't for me. I feel like I've made a great decision to move to graphic and web design - I'm happy and enjoy my work, rather than feel like it's a chore. So for those not sure whether they are on the right course, it's probably a sign that you're not! It's okay to move onto something else.

Besides, anything you do can only help you in the future.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[There were a few reasons why I decided to not pursue Architecture, and it came as a bit of a surprise to me and others.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>17</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-05-27 12:00:45]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-05-27 11:00:45]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[architecture-why-i-stopped]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[61]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Building My Own Website (Part 2 of 2)</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/06/23/building-my-own-website-part-2-of-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 11:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=19</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>A QUICK OVERVIEW OF PART 1</h2>
I had decided to create my own website from scratch as I was fed up of using a standard free portfolio site to display my work, and wanted to show off more of what I could do and get properly into web development. I had been refreshing my knowledge on HTML and CSS and teaching myself some new stuff, and I decided that I knew enough to build my own personal portfolio/website from scratch.

<!--more-->

Outlining the process of designing my website - most of it was quite straight forward and didn't take too long - was where I decided to end the previous post. Adding the javascript libraries that I have used was where I started running into trouble, and so I thought I would share how I overcame those problems seperately.
<h2>THE PROBLEMS I ENCOUNTERED AND OVERCOMING THEM</h2>
Most HTML and CSS websites are pretty basic, and creating a simple layout with a bit of content shouldn't take anyone with even a small amount of knowledge too long, so it was no wonder that everything up until this point (in other words, everything that I was used to doing) went without a hitch. It was when I was implementing the javascript libraries - JS being a new language to me - that the project time started ticking up. With any JS library there is bound to be some teething issues when first introducing it to your site (if there isn't then you are very lucky!), unless it was just me not reading the documentation correctly of course! Just ask anybody that knows me and they will gladly tell you of many times I have been wrong... (I can be quite stubborn sometimes and fight my argument to the very end).
<h3>Number 1</h3>
SO! The first problem I encountered was getting Masonry to work with my layout. This was probably the easiest problem to fix, as this one was just me not reading the documentation properly. The problem occured in the fact that I was trying to use Bootstrap for my collumn layout in the portfolio sections of my website, as well as Masonry. I wanted the same sizes and breakpoints throughout my site so it made sense at first to carry on using Bootstrap, but anybody that has used Masonry before will know that it has its own grid system - and trying to incorporate the both of them was just bound to fail. Anyway, to overcome this, I just re-read through the documentation and created the grid-sizers, and item (collumn) widths seperately in the css file for my portfolio pages. I then went into Bootstrap's own css file, got the breakpoints and recreated the item and grid-sizers for each of these same breakpoints. Simple, eh? Yeah, it was just me being<em>lazy</em>... bringing me onto my next problem (you'll get the pun in a second. Sorry).
<h3>Number 2</h3>
This one was a BIGGIE. I had just got Masonry all working nice and it was fully responsive. But then I thought - hold on a minute, some of my portfolio pages (more and more so going into the future) will end up having a hell of a lot of images on them and this could a) take a while to load and b) use up a lot of data for people viewing it on a phone/tablet. I didn't want to rape people's data allowance, so I needed to think of a way to stop all of those images loading at once, and thankfully somebody had already created this with LazyLoad. Brilliant, the perfect solution right? All I needed to do was add a 'lazy' class to any images that I wanted to not load until they had reached the fold of the browser window and change the 'src' to 'data-original' and replace the src with a small 1px image. Sounds too easy doesn't it? Well, you'd be right in thinking so. As soon as I did this it completely messed up my new and lovely Masonry layout and all of the images were overlapping each other right at the top of the page.

See, with LazyLoad, you replace all of your images with a 1px image in it's place, so downloading these uses minimal bandwitdth - almost zero. The JS then works its magic and when the top of the image gets to the fold of the window (or within a certain amount depending on the parameters you choose), it replaces the 'src' with the actual image source, thus only loading the images you can see and waiting to load all the other ones out of sight. Well, because all of my images were now technically only 1px tall, when Masonry was called to load once the page was ready, it pushes all of the images right to the top and thinks their containers (the 'items') were all 1px tall. This causes lots of overlapping and a lot more images are loaded than I wanted (because they are all above the fold already) - making the whole process pointless.

So what did I do to fix this issue? Well, the answer isn't as slick and fancy as I would have hoped it to have been. Unfortunately, it means having to layout all the items at the correct sizes for Masonry, while still keeping the 1px image for LazyLoad. This means that every time I upload a new image I need to set the item height manually. Obviously, with the width also being a variable (it's responsive remember!) I needed to do this with padding-bottom percentages. Et voila! Finding out the ratio for each individual image, and setting the padding-bottom percentage to this in each individual item's style meant that Masonry then reads the correct heights of each element, doing the layout correctly. Then LazyLoad can kick in and do its bandwidth saving magic.

&nbsp;

After these, everything seemed to go to plan and I didn't have much else to worry about, apart from a very few small things here and there. So, without further ado, I launched my website! Obviously, there were a couple of things that were pointed out to me by other people that I had missed, like the headers probably working better if they were fixed, but after a few weeks I think I had managed to get everything sorted.

After a couple of months though, I realised that maybe my website could do with being a bit of updating, and my SEO wasn't particularly good either, so I decided that I needed to start a blog. (Wahey it's here!) Unfortunately for me though, when I bought my hosting package I didn't realise that the basic package that I had bought didn't allow for Wordpress installation - I thought I might turn my website into a fully fledged Wordpress theme as I had built the main website now, and could work on the PHP I didn't know in the background. Well you can imagine my frustration when I realised that I couldn't even install Wordpress (I really should have done my research!) and would have to fork out some additional dollar for the upgrade I needed in a hosting package.

But wait a minute - don't most hosting packages include PHP? Yes, they do. But they don't all allow for databases to be created. So that got me thinking. If I really want to learn some PHP, it might even help to host my own blog too. So here it is! All hosted within my basic tiny package. (As of now anyway, I might need/ want to migrate over to Wordpress in the future just for ease of writing these posts). So I went away and taught myself a bit of PHP - turns out not much knowledge of it is needed, especially knowing some Javascript before hand - and built the building blocks of this blog.

&nbsp;

So there you have it - a full explanation of how I went about designing and building my personal website. Sorry for waffling on a bit...]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Why I decided to create a website for myself and the problems I came across doing it. Part 2 explains the major problems I encountered, how I fixed them, and doing my first bit of PHP with this blog!]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>19</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-06-23 12:00:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-06-23 11:00:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[building-my-own-website-part-2-of-2]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[60]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What a Graphic Designer Doesn&#039;t Want to Hear vs. The Perfect Client</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/08/24/what-a-graphic-designer-doesnt-want-to-hear-vs-the-perfect-client/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 11:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=21</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry it's been so long since my last post - I have been extremely busy recently.

Here's a little something to hopefully give any designers a little chuckle...

<!--more-->

And maybe, even for the non-designers, a go-to-guide on what not to say to a designer!

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/something-not-right.jpg" alt="I don't know what it is about it, but there's just something not quite right..." />
<div class="img-caption">Please, tell me more...</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/do-dont-like.jpg" alt="Here's a list of exactly what I do and don't like... and why" />
<div class="img-caption">Perfect! I'll get on those changes right away :)</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/look-pretty.jpg" alt="Just... make it look pretty" />
<div class="img-caption">The. Absolute. Worst.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/ideas-moodboard.jpg" alt="I have some ideas of what I want - here's a moodboard" />
<div class="img-caption">I think I love you.</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/comic-sans.jpg" alt="Can we try it in comic sans?" />
<div class="img-caption">Oh irony.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/anything-but-comic-sans.jpg" alt="Can we try it in a few different fonts. Anything but Comic Sans though!" />
<div class="img-caption">Legend.</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/illustrator-cartoons.jpg" alt="But you're one of those creative types... Why do I need an Illustrator to do these cartoons? Can't you?" />
<div class="img-caption">The same reason you aren't my lawyer, hairdresser <i>and</i> pilot.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/illustrator-friends.jpg" alt="Fair enough. Do you have any friends that are Illustrators that can do that work?" />
<div class="img-caption">Can we be friends?</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/google-image.jpg" alt="This image is perfect! I got it off google" />
<div class="img-caption">Don't worry about paying me, I'm done. Besides, you'll need to save for the lawsuit.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/found-images.jpg" alt="I've got a few images off google that are similar to what I would like for you to create" />
<div class="img-caption">Awesome! I'll have it done pronto!</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/design-logo.jpg" alt="I don't know what I want, but can you design me a logo?" />
<div class="img-caption">Next.</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/brief-logo.jpg" alt="I have a brief for you with a list of logos that I like" />
<div class="img-caption">Oh hi there :)</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/20-dimensions.jpg" alt="Brilliant! I think we've nailed the design. Now can I get that in these 20 different dimensions by tomorrow morning?" />
<div class="img-caption">Yeah sure, would you also like the answer to the meaning of life while I'm at it?</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/warning-dimensions.jpg" alt="Just to warn you before we start this project, I will be needing the image in these different dimensions..." />
<div class="img-caption">Thank you for warning me! I will plan accordingly.</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/sketch-final-logo.jpg" alt="Is this sketch the final logo? It's not very polished..." />
<div class="img-caption">*face palm*</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2015/images/initial-sketch-logo.jpg" alt="I relly like that initial idea, I can't wait to see the final design!" />
<div class="img-caption">Why thank you!</div>
</div>
</div>

I've had every single one of the bad ones, and not once any of the good ones.

Any outrageous remarks you've heard are more than welcome in the comments below!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[It's been a while since my last post - been super busy! Here's a little something to hopefully make some people chuckle, and maybe even give others a good education!]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>21</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-08-24 12:00:51]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-08-24 11:00:51]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[what-a-graphic-designer-doesnt-want-to-hear-vs-the-perfect-client]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[59]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>How Architecture Helped Me Get To Where I Am Now</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/10/26/how-architecture-helped-me-get-to-where-i-am-now/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 12:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=25</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<a title="Architecture - Why I Stopped" href="/blog/2015/05/27/architecture-why-i-stopped/">In another post</a> I explained why I stopped pursuing Architecture as a career path. It had been a long time plan of mine but when I got round to doing it I realised that it just wasn't for me. Despite this, I am so glad that I studied it for so many reasons - not least of which is that it greatly helped me get to where I am today.

<!--more-->

Now I wouldnt say that studying architecture gave me the skills that I use on a day to day basis - quite the opposite in fact, most of which I know is completely self taught - but it definitely helped me in my mindset, how I approach work, and on paper. It's certainly a conversation starter as well, I havent been to an interview yet that hasn't brought up the fact that I studied it, and why I didn't do it anymore. I'm always happy to talk about this and if anything I think it gives me an advantage because it shows that I know what I want and I'm not afraid to go after it, even if it would mean starting afresh.
<h2>WHAT EXACTLY DID IT TEACH ME THEN?</h2>
<h3>Thinking things through properly from the start</h3>
I think the biggest thing that I got out of it was the ability to think through a project from start to finish. Before I went to university, anything that I did (whether that was a piece of artwork, written work or a whole project), I would always just kind of 'do it'. I would wing a lot of the thinking and sometimes just even go back and make up a story about why I did something the way I did. I'm not afraid to admit this because I realised that it was a bad way of working, and I tended to be a lot prouder of my end result after doing something properly.

Architecture taught me to sit down at the beginnning of any project and think things through properly. I may not always write or sketch everything down for the smaller projects, but I would at least think things through a bit more before just diving in. With the bigger projects I will now properly sketch out ideas and from there delve a little bit deeper into a few of them, and then again wittle it down until the end result is something I can truly believe in.
<h3>Developing a concept</h3>
Leading on from the previous point, I learnt that developing a concept and thinking about every step you take and why you are doing it produces a much better outcome. With architecture, you just cannot afford not to do this, because you need to be so meticulous about every decision you make, or the design will just not work.

Knowing why you are making every decision you make means that there are no wrong decisions. Saying this though, I do think that not always knowing what you are doing can also be a great way to develop concepts. So if I feel like something isn't quite right with a design, I will sometimes just mess around, make mistakes and experiment a bit, because occasionally, good design can be just that - a happy accident.
<h3>Dealing with stress</h3>
It probably comes as no surprise to most people that architecture can be very stressful. Being able to deal with the constant stress was challenging at times, but the experience of doing that has helped me to handle other stressful situations with ease. (To be totally honest, I don't really get stressed out very easily and I think that might be because nothing has ever been quite as stressful since!)
<h3>Public speaking</h3>
When I was younger I would never be able to talk infront of other people. I would just constantly shake and never really manage to get any words out, let alone words that when strung together form a coherent sentence!

Having to present my work in critics every few weeks to new people every time has helped me deal with this. There was no avoiding it with architecture (it was part of the course) so I couldn't exactly back out. It was nerve racking enough having my work torn apart (it wasn't just me I swear! It's part of the way they do things - everyone's work was torn apart!) - let alone having to do it infront of 10-20 people. So this has helped me to speak more confidently infront of other people (albeit I do still get nervous every time).
<h2>HOW DID THIS ALL HELP THEN?</h2>
All of the things above have greatly helped me in becoming a more confident designer in general, and it can be applied to all walks of life, not just design.

So I think that without studying Architecture, I probably wouldnt be as confident, or commited to my work as much. And as hard as it was, and I'm definitely glad I made the decision to quit it, but it did really help me, and I'm also glad I made the decision to study it in the first place, because I don't think I would be where I am now if I hadn't.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Although I quit studying it, Architecture definitely helped in many ways to get me where I am now.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>25</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-10-26 12:00:54]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-10-26 12:00:54]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[how-architecture-helped-me-get-to-where-i-am-now]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[58]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Snowboarding - A Great Platform for Designers</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/11/13/snowboarding-a-great-platform-for-designers/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 12:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=27</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Sport as a whole is a great sector for designers to get involved in. There is so much out there that needs design input (especially now that sport and winter sports are becoming more mainstream and people care about their image while doing them), from the clothing that people wear, to the equipment that they use.

<!--more-->

Snowboarding though, in my opinion, creates a great platform for so many different types of design. Snowboarding is definitely seen as a 'cool' sport, and so inevitably, there comes a certain standard of looking good while doing it. The most obvious design influence for the sport is the board itself. There are loads of different brands out there, so there is plenty of choice in the actual physical quality of a board that for some people, the choice then sits on the design too.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<a href="http://www.lib-tech.com/snowboards/skate-banana/"><img src="http://cdn.lib-tech.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/1516-lib-Skate-Banana-Narrow-800x800.png" alt="Lib Tech Snowboard - Skate Banana" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">Lib Tech Skate Banana</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<a href="http://www.romesnowboards.com/boards/factory-rocker/"><img src="http://www.romesnowboards.com/images/boards/factory-rocker/158.jpg" alt="Rome Snowboard - Factory Rocker" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">Rome Snowboard Rocker</div>
</div>
</div>

Then there's the taste of boarders - which again can vary quite a lot. The majority of the sport is taken up by young males, but there is an ever increasing female side to the sport that needs to be addressed in the design too. Some boarders prefer the crazy busy artistic designs, and some prefer the much more conservative, clean graphical boards. Then there are the outright risqué ones with naked chicks on them, and also the cutsey ones that no 'duuude' would be seen dead riding.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<a href="http://www.boardistan.com/?p=2556"><img src="http://www.boardistan.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/burton-love-1-tm.jpg" alt="Burton Love Boards" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">An example of Burton's 'Love' line... causing controversy</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<a href="https://www.pinterest.com/pin/308848486920086366/"><img src="https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/736x/c6/66/7a/c6667ac125f48ab39e6f88fa56fbd944.jpg" alt="Roxy Board" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">Roxy is a women only brand</div>
</div>
</div>

But it's not just artists, photographers, and graphic designers that can benefit from the world of Snowboarding. Don't forget the clothes! How you look on and off the slopes can be quite important to boarders, and you get brands offering not only snowboard jackets and trousers but also hoodies, jeans, vests and even underwear!

So that's the artistic side covered, but there also other types of design that people can benfit from. All over the world there are many competitions for freestyle, and snowboarders are pushing the limits every day to how far and high they jump and the mental tricks they do on these jumps. So with the athletes pushing the sport further, you also need the park designers to make new and interesting parks every year for those top athletes. A prime example is the castle at <a href="http://nineknightssnow.com/">Susuki Nine Knights 2015.</a>

<div class="img-full">
<a href="http://nineknightssnow.com/"><img src="http://nineknightssnow.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/NineKnights2014_Day2_Seppe-Smits_Heli-Session_29_KlausPolzer_LowRes.jpg" alt="Nine Knights 2015 Castle" /></a>
<div class="img-caption">The reaction to this park was crazy and got some exciting lines out of it.</div>
</div>

Finally, I can't forget the snowboarders and engineers pushing the boards further and better every year. It seems like every season there's a new technology that has hit snowboard design to help cut those carving lines even better and give even more pop on those ollies. Easily the best board I've ridden though was a Lib Tech Banana board. Their <a title="Lib Tech technology" href="http://www.lib-tech.com/snowboarding/technology/">'Magne-traction'</a> on the edges cuts into the snow to make turning a breeze, and they handle themselves so well in all conditions. So for me, that has to be the best leap forward in snowboard engineering that nobody has beaten yet :) Their slogan isn't "World's Best Boards" for no reason!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Artists, Photographers, Graphic Designers, Park Designers, Fashion Designers, and engineers can all benefit from the world of snowboarding! There's so much design that goes into it and so many people can get involved! It's a great sport for any designer to have as a platform in their portfolio :)]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>27</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-11-13 12:00:18]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-11-13 12:00:18]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[snowboarding-a-great-platform-for-designers]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[56]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Funky Hover Effects (Desktop Only!)</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2015/11/18/funky-hover-effects-desktop-only/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2015 12:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=30</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<style type='text/css'>

#container-example {
  position: relative;
  margin-bottom: 50px;
}
#container-example *, #container-example *::after, #container-example *::before {
  box-sizing: border-box;
}
#container-example .strip {
  width: 100%;
  height: 300px;
  display: -webkit-box;
  display: -webkit-flex;
  display: -ms-flexbox;
  display: flex;
  -webkit-flex-wrap: wrap;
      -ms-flex-wrap: wrap;
          flex-wrap: wrap;
  -webkit-box-align: center;
  -webkit-align-items: center;
      -ms-flex-align: center;
          align-items: center;
  -webkit-justify-content: space-around;
      -ms-flex-pack: distribute;
          justify-content: space-around;
  background: #a3d7ef;
}
#container-example a {
  font-size: 12pt;
  font-family: sans-serif;
  color: #fff;
  text-decoration: none;
  letter-spacing: 2px;
  position: relative;
  text-align: center;
  padding: 15px 50px;
  width: 150px;
}
#container-example .colour-1 {
  background: #a3d7ef;
}
#container-example .colour-1 a::after {
  width: 100%;
  height: 0;
  background: #fff;
  content: '';
  position: absolute;
  top: 75%;
  left: 0;
  opacity: 0;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.3s ease-out;
  transition: all 0.3s ease-out;
  margin: auto;
}
#container-example .colour-1 a:hover::after {
  opacity: 1;
  top: 100%;
  height: 4px;
}
#container-example .colour-2 {
  background: #50cdb0;
}
#container-example .colour-2 a::before {
  content: '';
  width: 100%;
  height: 2px;
  background: #fff;
  position: absolute;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(45deg) scale(0.5);
          transform: rotate(45deg) scale(0.5);
  top: 50%;
  left: 0;
  opacity: 0.25;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.25s ease;
  transition: all 0.25s ease;
}
#container-example .colour-2 a::after {
  content: '';
  width: 100%;
  height: 2px;
  background: #fff;
  position: absolute;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(-45deg) scale(0.5);
          transform: rotate(-45deg) scale(0.5);
  top: 50%;
  left: 0;
  opacity: 0.4;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.25s ease;
  transition: all 0.25s ease;
}
#container-example .colour-2 a:hover::before {
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(-180deg);
          transform: rotate(-180deg);
  top: 100%;
}
#container-example .colour-2 a:hover::after {
  opacity: 1;
  -webkit-transform: rotate(180deg);
          transform: rotate(180deg);
  top: 0;
}
#container-example .colour-3 {
  background: #eb8c8c;
}
#container-example .colour-3 a {
  border: 2px solid #fff;
  background-size: 200% 100%;
  background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(left, #fff 50%, #eb8c8c 50%);
  background-image: linear-gradient(left, #fff 50%, #eb8c8c 50%);
  background-position: 100% 0;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.3s ease;
  transition: all 0.3s ease;
}
#container-example .colour-3 a:hover {
  background-position: 0;
  color: #eb8c8c;
}
#container-example .colour-4 {
  background: #8d78b1;
}
#container-example .colour-4 a {
  border: 2px solid #fff;
  border-radius: 50px;
  background-image: -webkit-linear-gradient(225deg, #fff, #fff 50%, #8d78b1 50%, #8d78b1);
  background-image: linear-gradient(-135deg, #fff, #fff 50%, #8d78b1 50%, #8d78b1);
  background-size: 100% 500%;
  background-position: bottom;
  -webkit-transition: all 0.4s ease;
  transition: all 0.4s ease;
}
#container-example .colour-4 a:hover {
  background-position: top;
  color: #8d78b1;
}

</style>

Playing around with some hover effects for desktop in CSS3

<!--more-->

Find the code for these at the bottom!
<div id="container-example">
<div class="strip colour-1"><a class="" href="">Lorem</a><a class="" href="">Ipsum</a><a class="" href="">Dolor</a></div>
<div class="strip colour-2"><a class="" href="">Lorem</a><a class="" href="">Ipsum</a><a class="" href="">Dolor</a></div>
<div class="strip colour-3"><a class="" href="">Lorem</a><a class="" href="">Ipsum</a><a class="" href="">Dolor</a></div>
<div class="strip colour-4"><a class="" href="">Lorem</a><a class="" href="">Ipsum</a><a class="" href="">Dolor</a></div>
</div>
<h2>html:</h2>
<div class="well">
<pre><code>&lt;div id="container-example"&gt;
  &lt;div class='strip colour-1'&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Lorem&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Dolor&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Sit&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Amet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='strip colour-2'&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Lorem&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Dolor&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Sit&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Amet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='strip colour-3'&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Lorem&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Dolor&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Sit&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Amet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='strip colour-4'&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Lorem&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Dolor&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Sit&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Amet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class='strip colour-5'&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Lorem&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Dolor&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Sit&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;a href=""&gt;Amet&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</code></pre>
</div>
<h2>scss:</h2>
<div class="well">
<pre><code>#container-example {
  position: relative;

  *, *::after, *::before {
    box-sizing: border-box;
  }

  .strip {
    width: 100%;
    height: 300px;
    display: flex;
    flex-wrap: wrap;
    align-items: center;
    justify-content: space-around;
    background: #a3d7ef;
  }

  a {
    font-size: 12pt;
    font-family: sans-serif;
    color: #fff;
    text-decoration: none;
    letter-spacing: 2px;
    position: relative;
    text-align: center;
    padding: 15px 50px;
    width: 150px;
  }

  .colour-1 {
    background: #a3d7ef;
    a::after {
      width: 100%;
      height: 0;
      background: #fff;
      content: '';
      position: absolute;
      top: 75%;
      left: 0;
      opacity: 0;
      transition: all 0.3s ease-out;
      margin: auto;
    }
    a:hover::after {
      opacity: 1;
      top: 100%;
      height: 4px;
    }
  }

  .colour-2 {
    background: #50cdb0;
    a::before {
      content: '';
      width: 100%;
      height: 2px;
      background: #fff;
      position: absolute;
      transform: rotate(45deg) scale(0.5);
      top: 50%;
      left: 0;
      opacity: 0.25;
      transition: all 0.25s ease;
    }
    a::after {
      content: '';
      width: 100%;
      height: 2px;
      background: #fff;
      position: absolute;
      transform: rotate(-45deg) scale(0.5);
      top: 50%;
      left: 0;
      opacity: 0.4;
      transition: all 0.25s ease;
    }
    a:hover::before {
      opacity: 1;
      transform: rotate(-180deg);
      top: 100%;
    }
    a:hover::after {
      opacity: 1;
      transform: rotate(180deg);
      top: 0;
    }
  }

  .colour-3 {
    background: #eb8c8c;
    a {
      border: 2px solid #fff;
      background-size: 200% 100%;
      background-image: linear-gradient(left, #fff 50%, #eb8c8c 50%);
      background-position: 100% 0;
      transition: all 0.3s ease;
    }
    a:hover {
      background-position: 0;
      color: #eb8c8c;
    }
  }

  .colour-4 {
    background: #8d78b1;
    a {
      border: 2px solid #fff;
      border-radius: 50px;
      background-image: linear-gradient(-135deg, #fff, #fff 50%, #8d78b1 50%, #8d78b1);
      background-size: 100% 500%;
      background-position: bottom;
      transition: all 0.4s ease;
    }
    a:hover {
      background-position: top;
      color: #8d78b1;
    }
  }
  
}
</code></pre>
</div>
Here is a link to the codepen (which includes additional effects!):
<a href="http://codepen.io/sebcglbailey/pen/mVVzEv">http://codepen.io/sebcglbailey/pen/mVVzEv</a>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Playing around with some hover effects for desktop in CSS3. With Code!]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>30</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2015-11-18 12:00:57]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2015-11-18 12:00:57]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[funky-hover-effects-desktop-only]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[55]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Always Judge A Book By Its Cover</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2016/03/15/always-judge-a-book-by-its-cover/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=32</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[No matter how many times your parents tell you not to judge a book by its cover, you always will. First impressions count in all counts of life, and no more is this apparent than in a book store or library (online and offline). Honestly, I spend more time in a bookstore admiring the different cover designs than I do actually reading the synopsis and trying to find an interesting read.

<!--more-->

There’s hundreds if not thousands of books on the shelves, and browsing them to choose your next read is a difficult choice. Humans naturally try and find the most efficient way of completing their task ahead, so I think it's fair to say that everybody, at least subconsciously, lets the covers of books sway their choice. So no matter what the saying is, it’s important to get the design of the cover right for your target audience to give the book the best possible chance.

This year, there is a ridiculous amount of excitement and hype (and rightly so - I’m certainly excited) about the upcoming Harry Potter sequel play<i>Harry Potter and the Cursed Child</i> and the prequel film <i>Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them.</i> So I wanted to focus on the journey the books have gone through over the years with their covers, and the impact I think the different designs had on the fans and general public. I also recently discovered the most recent ‘adult' covers that Bloomsbury released for the books, illustrated by <a href="http://www.andrewdavidsonillustration.com/">Andrew Davidson</a>, and was surprised how the redesign had gone largely unnoticed for the past 3 years.
<h2></h2>
<h2>THE FIRST SET OF 7</h2>
Let’s start with the first set of covers, or even just the first book - the one that started everything, <i>Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</i> - and the illustration drawn and painted by <a href="http://www.thomastaylor-author.com/">Thomas Taylor.</a> To start the series off, I don’t think the cover could have been any more perfect. It brilliantly encapsulates the curiosity of a wide-eyed 11 year old boy alighting a mysterious old train to a new world.
<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://img.neoseeker.com/mgv/293602/602/49/usa269x400harrypottercover_display.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone" />
<div class="img-caption">The original children's cover for Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://www.thompsonrarebooks.com/thompson/images/items/302694.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets" />
<div class="img-caption">The original children's cover for Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-poa.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban" />
<div class="img-caption">The original cover for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</div>
</div>
</div>

The book was written for and aimed at children the same age as Harry, and as such needed to include a sense of childish innocence. Who better to choose to illustrate the cover then, than an aspiring young artist barely out of university. It was certainly interesting to read how designing the first cover affected Thomas and his career at the time and since <a href="http://www.thomastaylor-author.com/me-and-harry-potter">on his blog.</a>

Unfortunately, or fortunately depending how you look at it, for Thomas, the book completely took off and the story of the scruffy haired wizard boy was on everybody’s lips. Because the book was getting so much attention, Bloomsbury decided to go with a more established illustrator for the next book <i>Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets.</i> <a href="http://cliffwright.co.uk/">Cliff Wright</a> also illustrated the third book <i>Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban.</i>

These two covers, being early on in Harry’s story still, I think work as they should. They still hold the childhood innocence and playful magic aura about them. These books are after all aimed at 11-14 year olds. They need to appeal to the younger audience – and the style of drawing, and subject matter of the covers do this.
<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="https://p3.liveauctioneers.com/930/21665/7457549_2_l.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
<div class="img-caption">The original cover for Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/7/70/Harry_Potter_and_the_Order_of_the_Phoenix.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix" />
<div class="img-caption">The original children's cover for Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-hbp.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince" />
<div class="img-caption">The original children's cover for Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-dh.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows" />
<div class="img-caption">The original cover for Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows</div>
</div>
</div>

The fourth book, <i>Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</i> designed by <a href="http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Giles_Greenfield">Giles Greenfield</a> starts to get a bit more serious as the target audience is really hitting their teens. The dragon on the front not only sums up one of the big scenes in the book, but also represents the increase in momentum and pace of the story with the rising of the main antagonist, Voldemort.

The next two books, <i>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</i> and <i>Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince,</i> designed by <a href="http://jasoncockcroft.co.uk/">Jason Cockcroft,</a> keep this momentum up and seriousness about the story high. For me though, these are the final covers that do the books justice. The last in the series, <i>Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows,</i> still designed by Jason Cockcroft, should have had a much more sombre and climactic design to it. Whereas, I think it has too much of a playful feel and doesn't really describe the seriousness and fast-paced element to the book.
<h3></h3>
<h2>ADULT COVERS</h2>
Meanwhile, the hype about the books had spread worldwide, and adults were starting to take a keen interest in the stories too. The success of the story was obvious to Bloomsbury, so they decided to release 'adult' covers so people could have the books out on show and not feel so embarrassed about reading a children's book. The first four of these covers featured black and white photorealistic images of various events or creatures, and in my opinion didn't really do the book any favours. The images were dull and didn't evoke any of that childhood fascination with magic that many of the adults reading the books were interested in in the first place.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://hyder-harry-potter.hostselect.net/pictures/the_philosophers_stone_adult.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://pictures.abebooks.com/isbn/9780747544074-uk-300.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://www.mugglenet.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/PoA.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/2/1165/4724128707_a38e03879d_b.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</div>
</div>
</div>

However, the next three books started incorporating colour into their covers and became more mystical in their artistic style. These covers are much better and really do bring back that joy that these books can bring to the older generation of readers. They also look much more professional, so not only does the reader not have to feel embarrassed holding it, but the cover would also peak the interest of others around and customers in book stores or libraries.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-op-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-hbp-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-dh-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows" />
<div class="img-caption">The original adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows</div>
</div>
</div>

I particularly like the final cover design as it captures the perfect amount of tenseness and curiosity that the story needs. These covers were much more successful and better designed, and so the first four books got re-designs of their adult covers too in a similar style.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-ps-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone" />
<div class="img-caption">The reworked adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-cs-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets" />
<div class="img-caption">The reworked adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-pa-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban" />
<div class="img-caption">The reworked adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-gf-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
<div class="img-caption">The reworked adult's cover for Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2>NEW CHILDREN'S COVERS</h2>
So it's been a while now since the last book came out in 2007, and there are children coming to the age where they can start reading the books that were only just born when this last book came out. It makes sense therefore, that there would be a resurgence in PR and art for the books to attract a completely new audience. With a plethora of different cover art from around the world, these new covers needed to stand out from the crowd and wow it's new and old audiences alike. And so, Bloomsbury decided to go with <a href="http://www.jonny-duddle.com/">Jonny Duddle</a> who was an already established illustrator and author of children's books himself.

There has been various debate and backlash about how Harry doesn't quite look like Harry on some of the covers (especially the later ones), but as he said himself in <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/harry-potter/11078077/How-Jonny-Duddle-re-imagined-Harry-Potter-for-a-new-generation.html">this Telegraph piece</a>, "He’s only meant to be 17, and he’s always described as being quite slight." But with so many people watching the movies, and unfortunately not reading the books, we have got used to Harry looking like Daniel Radcliffe!

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-ps-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-cs-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-pa-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-gf-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW covers for Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</div>
</div>
</div>

I not only love the new artistic approach to these new covers, but the new font used for the title is a great addition. Jonny Duddle managed to find his own style for Harry and his adventures, and didn't have to rely on any of the success of the movies to create a perfectly magical world to cover all 7 of the books. It's also intereting how none of the covers were just reworked artworks of the same scenes from the original covers. All of the scenes (except books 4 and 6) were completely new scenes from within the stories, but still just as important and enthralling for a passer-by as the originals, if not more so.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-op-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-hbp-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-dh-n.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW cover for Harry Potter and Deathly Hallows</div>
</div>
</div>

<h2>NEW ADULT'S COVERS</h2>
And finally this bring's me to the newest of the adult covers designed by <a href="http://www.andrewdavidsonillustration.com/">Andrew Davidson</a>. These covers are by far my favourite. Not only do they have stunning illustration work by Andrew which the designs were engraved in wood (see them <a href="http://www.andrewdavidsonillustration.com/engravings/03potter.html">here</a>), but the bright colours and beautiful typography used on the paperbacks is perfectly modern and bold that they wouldn't look out of place on any bookshelf. The graphic design of these are almost works of art in themselves that if I had the set (and I'm probably going to buy it, I'm not going to lie), I would seriously consider not reading them because they would looks so pristine up on my shelf.

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-ps-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-cs-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-pa-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-gf-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S covers for Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire</div>
</div>
</div>

<div class="img-container">
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-op-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-hbp-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and the Half-Blood Prince</div>
</div>
<div class="img-small">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/hp-and-dh-n-a.jpg" alt="Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows" />
<div class="img-caption">The NEW ADULT'S cover for Harry Potter and Deathly Hallows</div>
</div>
</div>

What really baffles me though is how these covers have gone largely unnoticed for the past 3 years. They started releasing these covers in 2013 and released them one by one, but the first I had heard of these was when I stumbled across them in Waterstone's the other day, which in turn prompted me to write this blog post. It's a shame really that these beautiful pieces of work could go unnoticed by so many, but just proves my point that a good book cover can stand out from a mile away and from within thousands of other books.

You can find an almost full list of the Harry Potter covers from most countries <a href="http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Cover_art">HERE</a>. Again, the new adult covers aren't included on this site, strangely! It's been 3 years people!]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Exploring the Harry Potter covers from the originals to the most recent adult covers and even the kindle editions. We are always taught not to judge a book by its cover, but that doesn't meant that a book cover isn't extremely important and the design of it matters!]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>32</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-03-15 12:00:25]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-03-15 12:00:25]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[always-judge-a-book-by-its-cover]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[54]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Adobe Xd Review</title>
		<link>http://localhost:8888/blog/2016/04/24/adobe-xd-review/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[sebcglbailey]]></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://localhost:8888/blog/?p=35</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[So it's been a little over a month now since Adobe launched their new 'Experience Design' software, Adobe Xd. Needless to say there was a fair amount of excitement over the launch of this product ever since it was unveiled as <a href="http://blogs.adobe.com/creativecloud/introducing-project-comet-a-new-tool-for-designing-and-prototyping-user-experiences">'Project Comet'</a> at Adobe MAX 2015.

<!--more-->

The new tool promised to face 'today's UX design challenges' and aid designers with 'wireframing, visual design, prototyping, and previewing all in one.' And to be honest, at a first go of it, I think Adobe have done pretty damn well.

<div class="img-full">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/xd-00.jpg" alt="My first run at Adobe Xd" />
<div class="img-caption">My first run at Adobe Xd and UX design in general</div>
</div>

Now, I'm fairly new to the UX world, but I've done my fair share of wireframing in my time as a designer, and I've always found it to be a bit of a struggle with the tools that I've had at my disposal. I've never been a 'UX Designer' so have not quite got round to using the wireframing products that Adobe are trying to dethrone (yes, I'm looking at you Sketch), but using Adobe's creative suite has always been a bit of an uphill struggle with trying to get a bunch of wireframe views out quickly. It's just not something they are built for.

So when I heard that Xd was being released I was super keen to give it a go. I downloaded it on day 2 of it being out, and by the end of day 4 I had already thrown together a bunch of good-quality wireframe designs for my new <a href="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/graphic-design">X-Games app design</a> idea.

<div class="img-full">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/xd-01.jpg" alt="X-Games wireframe views" />
<div class="img-caption">Full-Colour Wireframing Views for my X-Games Aspen App Design</div>
</div>

I found the product so easy to pick up, due to my experience with Photoshop, Illustrator and InDesign – all of the tools were intuitive and I knew exactly where to find what I needed. The smart guides seem to work so much smoother than those in the other programs, and the because of this, the wireframes very quickly turned into full-coloured designs. (In fact, the wireframes didn't really last long at all, it was so quick to mock things up I found myself wireframing in full-colour and using the graphics that I had already designed instead of placeholders).

That's another great thing about Xd. It seemlessly integrates with Illustrator so I could just copy all of my vector graphics over into my design, and they were still fully editable with stroke and fill being quickly updated.

Now don't get me wrong, it certainly had it's limitations. But what do you expect from a completely new product? Starting out with such a simple and limited programme is only going to help Adobe in the future. They've given us a basis, with a very basic set of tools (that are great and quick to use), and they are adding to it bit by bit – listening to what the designers themselves that are using the product want.

<div class="img-full">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/xd-02.jpg" alt="Adobe Xd prototyping mode" />
<div class="img-caption">Adove Xd Prototyping Mode with hotspots</div>
</div>

One of my favourite, and also most irritating features of Xd was the prototyping mode. I loved that I was able to really quickly mock-up what the app could look like and create hotspots to move from screen to screen. But the limitations of this tool very quickly became apparent.
<ul>
 	<li>You can't create scrollable areas – I wanted to include a list of athletes/artists and was limited to just showing a few.</li>
 	<li>Another scrollable area I would have liked to have seen is slideshows.</li>
 	<li>I couldn't create a menu that slides out from the side – I ended up having to just create a seperate view for the menu, with the home screen visible in the background. This made the transition from home screen to menu less than favourable.</li>
 	<li>There were no microinteractions – I would have liked to have seen transition states between two elements on the same page, and also a tab function where only part of the view updates and not the whole screen.</li>
 	<li>The transitions between pages is limited to slide and fade – it would be nice to have a couple more thrown in there.</li>
</ul>
Other than these, however, I did find the prototype tool very useful in seeing what the app could possibly look like, and had a lot of fun flicking between the pages of my prototype (and was still in a little bit of awe that I could mock something up so quickly).

<div class="img-full">
<img src="http://sebastianbailey.co.uk/blog/2016/images/xd-03.jpg" alt="Prototype page transitions" />
<div class="img-caption">Prototype page transitions with X-Games Menu screen as completely seperate view – one of my initial disappointments with the software.</div>
</div>

So as a starting point, I think Adobe have hit the nail on the head with this one, and I am very excited to see where the product goes – and I for one will certainly be using it a lot in the future.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[My first proper dive into UX design and I decided to give Adobe's new Xd software a go and after a month of using it and it being out there for people to experiment with, I've decided to give it a review.]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>35</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date><![CDATA[2016-04-24 12:00:50]]></wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt><![CDATA[2016-04-24 11:00:50]]></wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status><![CDATA[open]]></wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name><![CDATA[adobe-xd-review]]></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status><![CDATA[publish]]></wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type><![CDATA[post]]></wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password><![CDATA[]]></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorised"><![CDATA[Uncategorised]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_edit_last]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key><![CDATA[_thumbnail_id]]></wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[53]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
